Finding aid for the Wanda Coleman papers LSC.2282
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1960-2013
  - Correspondence, 2004-2006 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2005-2007 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2007-2008 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2007-2009 (Box 54, Folder 4-5)
    Contains correspondence regarding 2008 benefit for poet Will Alexander.
  - Correspondence, 2009 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Includes CD of Coleman reading.
    File contains one compact disc. Audiovisual materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. To review these audiovisual materials, you must notify the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk in advance of your visit.
  - Correspondence, 2011 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 2011-2012 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    Contains a "self-interview" published by The Nervous Breakdown.
  - Correspondence, 2013 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Blurbs, 1988-2002 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    Contains requests for and correspondence regarding book blurbs for Mike Davis, Timothy Joyce, Tony Medina, Merilene Murphy, The Outlaw Bible of American Poetry, and Lisa Teasley.
  - Correspondence: Cassettes (Gail Hawkins), 1995 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Cassettes (Roy Schneider), 1990 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Cassettes (Diane Toomey), c. 1995 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Cassettes (Jeanne Spicuzzo), 1996 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Christmas cards, 2005-2009 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Fan Letters, 1992-2012 (Box 39, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence: Invoices, Rights, Permissions, 2001-2007 (Box 50, Folder 2-3)
  - Correspondence: Invoices, Rights, Permissions (A-P), 2000-2007 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Invoices, Rights, Permissions (P-W), 2001-2005 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: PR, 2011-2012 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Rolodex, 1981-2002 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Rolodex (address book 1, A-E), c. 1980 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Rolodex (address book 1, F-Z), c. 1975 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Rolodex (address book 2, A-J), c. 1980 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Rolodex (address book 2, K-Z), c. 1980 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Submissions (A-E, Binder 1), 1981-2002 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Submissions (F-M, Binder 1), 1974-2001 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Submissions (O-S, Binder 1), 1980-2003 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    Contains note regarding Coleman's many submissions to Poetry Magazine.
  - Correspondence: Submissions (S-W, Binder 1), 1976-1998 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Submissions (AB-BL, Binder 2), 1968-1995 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Submissions (BL-BR, Binder 2), 1968-1995 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Submissions (CA-EN, Binder 2), 1970-1988 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Submissions (ES-IS, Binder 2), 1969-1996 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    Includes many originals of early poems and short stories sent to magazines such as Essence and Poetry, and associated correspondence.
  - Correspondence: Submissions (JO-SE, Binder 2), 1969-2000 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    Includes many originals of early poems and short stories.
  - Correspondence: Submissions (SH-ZE, Binder 2), 1969-2000 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Submissions, 1975-2012 (Box 39, Folder 5-6, Box 40, Folder 1-3)
  - Correspondence: Submissions (anthologies, AF), 1990-2004 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Submissions (anthologies, AI-BE), 1980-2002 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Submissions (anthologies, BL-E), 1989-2004 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Submissions (anthologies, E-G), 1990-2004 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Submissions (anthologies, H-J), 1989-2002 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Submissions (anthologies, J-N), 1990-2007 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Submissions (anthologies, L-P), 1985-2011 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Submissions (anthologies, P-S), 1985-2008 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Submissions (anthologies, T-Z), 1988-2008 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Submissions (United States Artists), 2007-2012 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Submissions (acceptances and readings), 1975-1981 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    Contains a log of poems submitted to and accepted by journals, as well as some notes by Coleman regarding her experiences at readings during this time period.
  - Correspondence: Submissions (film, TV, theater), 1973-2007 (Box 44, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence: Submissions (Guggenheim), 1981-1983 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Submissions (Guggenheim), 1984 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Submissions (Guggenheim), 1984-1991 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Submissions (rejection slips), 1963-1968 (Box 46, Folder 5)
- Series 2: Works by Wanda Coleman, 1961-2012
  Many drafts of published and unpublished works by Wanda Coleman: poetry, fiction, nonfiction, spoken word, film, television and theater writings, and juvenilia, as well as volumes edited by Coleman. Includes related correspondence and digital materials. Highlights include correspondence with John Martin at Black Sparrow Press regarding her publications there, many unproduced screenplays, and unpublished collections of poetry and short stories.
  Series is broken into subseries by genre, and each is ordered chronologically. Within subseries 2.1-2.3 (poetry, fiction, nonfiction), published manuscripts lead the series, followed by unpublished manuscripts, then individual drafts.
  - Poetry, 1968-2010
    Published and unpublished collections of Coleman's poetry, as well as drafts of individual poems. The drafts, which appear and the end of the series, are organized chronologically and include both published and unpublished poems with Coleman's edits.. Includes related correspondence. Materials for Coleman's collection of poems Ostinato Vamps (2003) are not included.
    SOME ITEMS IN THIS SUBSERIES HAVE BEEN DIGITIZED. Please contact the reference desk for details on arranging access.
    - Bibliography (alphabetical), 1979-1997 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Bibliography (alphabetical, includes other genres), 1969-1995 (Box 57)
    - Bibliography (rolodex, includes other genres), 1970-2010 (Box 149, Folder 3-4)
    - Sparrow 59 (Art in the Court of the Blue Fag), 1977 (Box 56, Folder 2)
      Includes correspondence with John Martin and a signed copy of the chapbook with Coleman's notes.
    - Sparrow 59 (Art in the Court of the Blue Fag), 1977 (Box 56, Folder 3)
      Includes correspondence with John Martin and Diane Wakoski, and reviews.
    - Mad Dog Black Lady Frothing (original manuscript), 1976 (Box 56, Folder 4-5)
    - Mad Dog Black Lady Frothing (work manuscript), 1974-1978 (Box 56, Folder 6-8)
    - Mad Dog Black Lady (proofs), 1978 (Box 58, Folder 2-3)
      Contains correspondence with John Martin.
    - Mad Dog Black Lady, 1978-1989 (Box 58, Folder 4)
      Materials relating to the book's publication, including photos from the publication party, correspondence, and reviews.
    - Four Poems (first and second editions, signed), c.1977 (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Four Poems (second and third editions, signed), c. 1977 (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - Four Poems (fourth edition, signed), c. 1977 (Box 84, Folder 6)
    - Imagoes (original manuscript), 1980 (Box 58, Folder 6-7, Box 59, Folder 1)
      Includes letter to John Martin.
    - Imagoes (work manuscript 1), 1980 (Box 59, Folder 2-3)
    - Imagoes (work manuscript 2), 1980 (Box 59, Folder 4-6)
    - Imagoes (second draft), 1980 (Box 59, Folder 7-8)
    - Imagoes (first proofs), c. 1981 (Box 60, Folder 2, Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Imagoes (second proofs), c. 1981 (Box 60, Folder 3-4)
    - Imagoes (final proofs), c. 1982 (Box 57)
    - Nothing Can Shatter Night (editor), 1981-1985 (Box 61, Folder 1)
      Coleman's edits of poet Patrick Bianucci's manuscript and correspondence regarding her efforts to get it published.
    - Alligator in Lace (editor), c. 1982 (Box 61, Folder 2)
      Early version of Susannah Foster manuscript Coleman edited.
    - Earthbound in Betty Grable's Shoes (editor) (original manuscript), 1983 (Box 61, Folder 3-4)
      Includes Coleman's introduction to the volume of poetry by Susannah Foster she edited and worked to have published.
    - Earthbound in Betty Grable's Shoes (editor) (work manuscript 1), c. 1983 (Box 61, Folder 5-6)
      Includes Coleman's edits to Foster's manuscript.
    - Earthbound in Betty Grable's Shoes (editor) (work manuscript 2), c. 1983 (Box 63, Folder 1, Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Earthbound in Betty Grable's Shoes (editor) (second proofs), c. 1984 (Box 62)
    - Earthbound in Betty Grable's Shoes (editor) (Foster notebooks), c. 1982 (Box 63, Folder 2-3)
    - Earthbound in Betty Grable's Shoes (editor) (correspondence), 1981-1994 (Box 63, Folder 4-5)
    - Earthbound in Betty Grable's Shoes (editor) (memorabilia), 1974-1991 (Box 63, Folder 6, Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Earthbound in Betty Grable's Shoes (editor) (Coleman essay), c. 1982 (Box 64, Folder 2-3)
    - Earthbound in Betty Grable's Shoes (editor) (manuscript rejects), 1970-1980 (Box 64, Folder 4-5)
    - Heavy Daughter Blues (original manuscript/correspondence), 1985-1988 (Box 60, Folder 5)
      Includes correspondence with John Martin and author photo.
    - Heavy Daughter Blues (original manuscript), c. 1985 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Heavy Daughter Blues (drafts), 1984 (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Heavy Daughter Blues (work manuscript 1), 1984 (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - Heavy Daughter Blues (work manuscript 2), c. 1985 (Box 57)
    - Heavy Daughter Blues (work manuscript 3), 1985 (Box 60, Folder 9-10)
    - Heavy Daughter Blues (first proofs), c. 1986 (Box 62)
    - Heavy Daughter Blues (second proofs), c. 1986 (Box 62)
    - Dicksboro Hotel, 1988-1990 (Box 65, Folder 1)
      Includes correspondence with Murray Wolfe of Ambrosia Press, the publisher, and a letter from John Martin.
    - African Sleeping Sickness (work manuscript), 1990 (Box 65, Folder 2-4)
    - African Sleeping Sickness (correspondence), 1985-1992 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - African Sleeping Sickness (original manuscript), 1990 (Box 66, Folder 1, Box 65, Folder 6-7)
    - African Sleeping Sickness (first proofs-work copy), 1990 (Box 67)
    - African Sleeping Sickness (first proofs), 1990 (Box 67)
    - African Sleeping Sickness (second proofs), 1990 (Box 67)
    - African Sleeping Sickness (final proofs), c. 1990 (Box 68)
    - African Sleeping Sickness (rejects), 1992-1995 (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Hand Dance (correspondence/Coleman second edit), c. 1992 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Hand Dance (Coleman 2nd edit), c. 1992 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Hand Dance (Austin Straus edit), c. 1992 (Box 66, Folder 4-5)
    - Hand Dance (work copy), c. 1992 (Box 66, Folder 6, Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Hand Dance (first proofs-copy one), c. 1992 (Box 68)
    - Hand Dance (first proofs-copy two), c. 1992 (Box 70)
    - Hand Dance (second proofs), c. 1992 (Box 70)
    - Hand Dance (final proofs), c. 1992 (Box 68)
    - Bathwater Wine (work manuscript), c. 1997 (Box 69, Folder 2-4)
      This manuscript, which eventually became Bathwater Wine, is titled God Bless The Fire.
    - Bathwater Wine (American Sonnets), 1994-1997 (Box 69, Folder 5-7)
    - Bathwater Wine (Lotus Press Submission), 1997 (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - Bathwater Wine (correspondence and original manuscript), 1997-1998 (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - Bathwater Wine (original manuscript), 1997 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Bathwater Wine (first proofs), 1998 (Box 71, Folder 2-4)
    - Bathwater Wine (second proofs), 1998 (Box 71, Folder 5-7)
    - Mercurochrome (correspondence and first rough), 1999-2001 (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Mercurochrome (first rough), 2000 (Box 72, Folder 1-2)
    - Mercurochrome (first proofs), 2000 (Box 70)
    - Mercurochrome (second proofs), 2000 (Box 73)
    - Mercurochrome (final proofs-copy one), 2001 (Box 72, Folder 3-4)
    - Mercurochrome (final proofs-copy two), 2001 (Box 73)
    - Greatest Hits 1966-2003, 2003-2004 (Box 72, Folder 5-6)
      Includes correspondence with Pudding House Press, the chapbook's publisher.
    - The World Falls Away (correspondence), 2003-2011 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - The World Falls Away (draft two), 2003 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - The World Falls Away (drafts two-four), 2003 (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - The World Falls Away (first proofs), 2011 (Box 73)
    - The World Falls Away (final proofs), 2011 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - The Love Project (correspondence), 2001-2013 (Box 184, Folder 8, Box 74, Folder 4)
      The Love Project is a collaboration between Coleman and her husband, Austin Straus. Includes correspondence with the publisher, Red Hen Press, and drawings from the book (some originals and some copies).
    - The Love Project (draft), c. 2000 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - The Love Project (manuscript), c. 2000 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - The Love Project (work copy), c. 2003 (Box 184, Folder 6)
    - The Love Project (work copy w/edits), c. 2012 (Box 184, Folder 4)
    - The Love Project (final proofs), 2013 (Box 184, Folder 5)
    - The Love Project (submission copy and correspondence), 2003-2005 (Box 184, Folder 7)
    - Keeper of the Ankh, c. 1968 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Shades of Blackness, c. 1968 (Box 77, Folder 2-3)
    - Unpublished Manuscripts, 1973-1976 (Box 77, Folder 4)
      Two early unpublished manuscripts titled Midnight Carries Me South Along Illusion Avenue and My Anger, My Prison.
    - Unpublished Manuscripts, c. 1976 (Box 77, Folder 5)
      Early unpublished manuscripts titled The Laying Down Blues and Other Laments: black blue street verse and A Gun Full of Bullets.
    - Corners, 1978 (Box 77, Folder 6, Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Spit, Bullets, and Profanities, 1978 (Box 78, Folder 2-3)
    - Growing Up Black, 1981 (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Loud Music, c. 1986 (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - God Bless the Fire, 1996 (Box 109, Box 79, Folder unknown container)
    - Sorceress of Muntu (work manuscript), 1998 (Box 78, Folder 6-7)
    - Sorceress of Muntu, 1998 (Box 80, Folder 1-3)
    - Selected Early Poems, c. 2000 (Box 80, Folder 4-6)
    - Azrael, 1998-2000 (Box 81, Folder 1-3, Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Spirit Walk (work manuscript), 2000 (Box 81, Folder 4-6)
    - Spirit Walk, 2003 (Box 81, Folder 7, Box 82, Folder 1-2)
    - Drafts, 1966-1970 (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Drafts, 1968-1970 (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Drafts, 1970-1972 (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - Drafts, 1973 (Box 82, Folder 6-7)
    - Drafts, 1974 (Box 82, Folder 8)
    - Drafts, 1975 (Box 83, Folder 1-3)
    - Drafts, 1973-1994 (Box 83, Folder 4-7)
    - Drafts, 1976-1977 (Box 84, Folder 1-3)
    - Work Book 2, 1976-1997 (Box 85, Folder 1-2)
    - Drafts, 1978 (Box 85, Folder 3-4)
    - Drafts, 1979 (Box 85, Folder 5-6)
    - Drafts, 1980 (Box 86, Folder 1-2)
    - Drafts, 1981 (Box 86, Folder 3-4)
    - Drafts, 1981-1984 (Box 86, Folder 5-7)
    - Drafts, 1984-1986 (Box 87, Folder 1-4)
    - Drafts, 1984-1999 (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Drafts, 1988 (Box 88, Folder 1-2)
    - Drafts, 1989 (Box 88, Folder 3-4)
    - Drafts, 1980-1989 (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Drafts, 1990 (Box 88, Folder 5-8)
    - Drafts, 1991-1993 (Box 89, Folder 1-3)
    - Drafts, 1994-1997 (Box 90, Folder 1, Box 89, Folder 4-6)
    - Drafts, 1997-1998 (Box 90, Folder 2-5)
    - Drafts, 1999-2001 (Box 90, Folder 6)
    - Drafts, 2010 (Box 90, Folder 7)
    - "Bathsheba's Psalm", 2010 (Box 129, Folder 4)
      Drafts of and correspondence relating to "Bathsheba's Psalm," an unpublished translation intended for an anthology of Anglo-Saxon poems.
    - Women's Building Anthology (editor), 1970-1999 (Box 90, Folder 8)
  - Fiction, 1975-2012
    Published and unpublished novels and short story collections, as well as individual drafts of stories. Includes related correspondence.
    - A War of Eyes (correspondence), 1986-1996 (Box 90, Folder 9)
    - A War of Eyes (draft), c. 1986 (Box 91, Folder 1-3)
    - A War of Eyes (original manuscript 1), 1987 (Box 91, Folder 4-5)
    - A War of Eyes (original manuscript 2), c. 1987 (Box 79)
    - A War of Eyes (first proofs), 1988 (Box 91, Folder 6-7)
    - A War of Eyes (second proofs), 1988 (Box 79)
    - Mambo Hips and Make Believe (Fourzon materials), 1975-1989 (Box 91, Folder 8, Box 92, Folder 1)
      Coleman drew on the biography of and her correspondence with Pamela Fourzon in writing Mambo.
    - Mambo Hips and Make Believe (research/notes), c. 1995 (Box 92, Folder 2-4)
    - Mambo Hips and Make Believe (section drafts/notes), 1999 (Box 93, Folder 1-4, Box 92, Folder 5-6)
    - Mambo Hips and Make Believe (first draft), 1998-1999 (Box 94, Folder 1-4, Box 93, Folder 5-6)
    - Mambo Hips and Make Believe (first draft, Kaliui edit), 1999 (Box 95, Folder 1-4, Box 94, Folder 5-6)
    - Mambo Hips and Make Believe (second draft), 1999 (Box 95, Folder 5-6, Box 96, Folder 1-3)
    - Mambo Hips and Make Believe (work rough), 1999 (Box 97, Folder 1-3, Box 96, Folder 4-5)
    - Mambo Hips and Make Believe (master copy), 1999 (Box 97, Folder 4-6, Box 98, Folder 1-3)
    - Mambo Hips and Make Believe (first proofs), 1999 (Box 98, Folder 4-6)
    - Mambo Hips and Make Believe (first proofs, Straus), 1999 (Box 98, Folder 7, Box 99, Folder 1-3)
    - Mambo Hips and Make Believe (second proofs), 1999 (Box 100)
    - Jazz and Twelve O'Clock Tales (correspondence), 2007 (Box 99, Folder 4-7)
      Includes advance reading copy.
    - Jazz and Twelve O'Clock Tales (work manuscript), 1983-1985 (Box 101, Folder 1-2)
    - Jazz and Twelve O'Clock Tales (draft), 2001 (Box 184, Folder 9-11, Box 100)
      ITEMS IN BOX 184 HAVE BEEN DIGITIZED. Please contact the reference desk for details on arranging access.
    - Jazz and Twelve O'Clock Tales (revision), 2006 (Box 101, Folder 3-4)
    - Jazz and Twelve O'Clock Tales (manuscript), 2007 (Box 101, Folder 5-7)
    - Novel Ideas, 1975-1977 (Box 102, Folder 1)
    - Story Ideas, 1985-2006 (Box 102, Folder 2-3)
    - Mama Sin Sin, c. 1977 (Box 102, Folder 4-5)
    - The Saturday Night's Over and Charlie Says He Loves Me, Blues (second rough), 1972 (Box 102, Folder 6)
    - The Saturday Night's Over and Charlie Says He Loves Me, Blues (third rough), 1980 (Box 102, Folder 7)
    - The Saturday Night's Over and Charlie Says He Loves Me, Blues (work manuscript 1985) (Box 103, Folder 1-2)
    - The Saturday Night's Over and Charlie Says He Loves Me, Blues (work manuscript 1985, copy 2) (Box 103, Folder 3-4)
    - The Saturday Night's Over and Charlie Says He Loves Me, Blues (second rewrite), c. 1986 (Box 103, Folder 5-7)
    - The Saturday Night's Over and Charlie Says He Loves Me, Blues (manuscript), c. 1986 (Box 104, Folder 1-4)
    - Late Night Drives, c. 1988 (Box 104, Folder 5-6)
    - Clowns and Wild Birds (editor), 1997-2000 (Box 104, Folder 7)
      Coleman edited and promoted this volume of Susannah Foster's stories and "miscellany."
    - Jazzmine and Silent Nights (editor), c. 2000 (Box 104, Folder 8)
      Alternate version of Coleman's edition of Susannah Foster's collected stories and prose.
    - Where The Sun Don't Shine, c. 2003 (Box 100)
      Unpublished volume of collected late stories.
    - The 13th of Never, c. 2003 (Box 146, Folder 5-6)
    - Liver Lips Sonata, 2006-2008 (Box 105, Folder 1-3)
    - Stories, 1970-1979 (Box 105, Folder 4)
    - Stories, 1970-1985 (Box 105, Folder 5-6)
    - Stories, 1984-1988 (Box 106, Folder 1-5, Box 107, Folder 1, Box 123, Folder 1-7)
    - Stories ("Shades of Black"), 1987 (Box 107, Folder 2)
    - Stories ("Shark Liver Oil"), 1999 (Box 107, Folder 3)
    - Stories, 2000-2012 (Box 107, Folder 4-7, Box 108, Folder 1-4)
  - Nonfiction, 1973-2012
    Published essay collections, as well as individual essays, articles, and book reviews, such as Coleman's controversial review of Maya Angelou's A Song Flung Up to Heaven. There is a large quantity of material from her time as a columnist at the Los Angeles Times. Includes related correspondence.
    SUBSERIES CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. To review these audiovisual materials, you must notify the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk in advance of your visit.
    - Native in a Strange Land (book proposal, rough), 1993 (Box 109)
    - Native in a Strange Land (correspondence), 1994-1996 (Box 110, Folder 1)
    - Native in a Strange Land (book proposal), c. 1994 (Box 110, Folder 2-4)
    - Native in a Strange Land (drafts/research), c. 1997 (Box 111, Folder 1-2, Box 110, Folder 5-7)
    - Native in a Strange Land (original manuscript), c. 1993 (Box 109, Box 111, Folder 3-4)
      Bound volume contains some related correspondence.
    - Native in a Strange Land (work rough), 1996 (Box 111, Folder 5-8, Box 112, Folder 1-2)
    - Native in a Strange Land (first proofs, author's), 1996 (Box 112, Folder 3-4)
    - Native in a Strange Land (first proofs, copy 1), 1996 (Box 112, Folder 5-7)
    - Native in a Strange Land (first proofs, copy 3), 1996 (Box 112, Folder 8-9, Box 113, Folder 1)
    - Native in a Strange Land (second proofs), 1996 (Box 113, Folder 2-3)
    - Native in a Strange Land (second proofs, copy 2), 1996 (Box 113, Folder 4-5)
    - The Riot Inside Me (correspondence), 2003-2006 (Box 113, Folder 6-8)
    - The Riot Inside Me (work rough), c. 2004 (Box 114, Folder 1-4)
    - The Riot Inside Me (final proofs), 2005 (Box 184, Folder 1-3)
    - High Performance (correspondence), 1992-2009 (Box 115, Folder 1, Box 114, Folder 5-6)
      On behalf of the Multi-Ethnic Coalition of Los Angeles Artists, Coleman edited a special issue of High Performance magazine, "The Verdict and the Violence" (1992). A companion CD was also made. Includes digital media.
      Box 115, folder 1 contains four microcassettes. Audiovisual materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. To review these audiovisual materials, you must notify the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk in advance of your visit.
    - High Performance (submissions/drafts), 1992 (Box 115, Folder 2-7)
    - High Performance (copy and CDs), 1992 (Box 116, Folder 1)
      File contains four compact discs. Audiovisual materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. To review these audiovisual materials, you must notify the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk in advance of your visit.
    - Seoul to Soul, 1993 (Box 116, Folder 4)
    - Los Angeles Times, 1989-2000 (Box 116, Folder 5-7, Box 118, Folder 1-6, Box 117, Box 120, Folder 1-2, Box 119, Folder 1-7)
    - Maya Angelou review, 2002 (Box 120, Folder 3-6)
      Drafts and correspondence relating to Coleman's controversial review of Maya Angelou's A Song Flung Up to Heaven in the Los Angeles Times. Also includes Coleman's annotated copy of Song and other books by Angelou.
    - "Book of Memories", 1979-2012 (Box 149, Folder 5-8, Box 121, Folder 1)
      Notes and writings gathered by Coleman for the purpose of writing her memoirs.
    - Drafts, 1973-1979 (Box 121, Folder 2-3)
    - Drafts, 1980-1989 (Box 121, Folder 4-6, Box 122, Folder 1-7, Box 124, Folder 1)
    - "Poetry, Race, and the Power to Change The World", 1984-1985 (Box 124, Folder 2)
    - "Baby Boomers", 1984-1990 (Box 124, Folder 3-5)
    - "On Theloniousism", c. 1987 (Box 125)
    - Drafts, 1984-1990 (Box 126, Folder 1-2, Box 124, Folder 6-8)
    - Drafts, 1990-1999 (Box 126, Folder 3-7, Box 127, Folder 1-4)
    - "Dear Mama", 1995-1997 (Box 127, Folder 5)
    - "Dancer on a Blade", 1997-1998 (Box 127, Folder 6-7, Box 128, Folder 1-2)
    - "For Dad", 1998-2001 (Box 128, Folder 3)
    - "Avant-Garde With Mainstream Tendencies", 2000-2001 (Box 128, Folder 4-5)